目标已找到
Target acquired.
收到,目标确定,随时开火
Roger that. Target confirmed. Fire at will.
辨认目标,下士
Make your target, corporal.
各位,你们时间有限
You got a time problem, gentlemen.
锁定地形参考系统,赶快准备好
Lock it, t.R.S. And get this over with.
地形参考系统在确认目标
T.r.s. Verifying target.
妈的,瞄准目标就扣扳机啦
Just eyeball the fucker and pull the trigger.
我听到了,贝克特
I heard that, Beckett.
好像有敌人进入了
We got incoming bogeys.
收到,650公尺
Range, 650 yards.
风速每小时5公里
We have a 5-mile-an-hour wind,
中范围,来自左侧
midrange, coming from your Lima.
正在尝试确认目标
Attempting to confirm target.
长官,艾佛斯的脉搏、呼吸和 皮肤电反应已达到最高
Sir, evers's pulse, respiration and g.S.R. Are maxing out.
贝克特呢?
What about Beckett?
没有,很稳定
No, steady as a rock.
像在睡眠中一样
It's like he's taking a nap.
各位,快没时间了
You're running out of time, gentlemen.
艾佛斯,开枪
Take the shot, evers.
可能会射到人质,军械官…
I could hit a hostage, master gunny...
叫你开枪就开枪
Take the fucking shot.
别轻举妄动
Stand down.
各位,别轻举妄动
Stand down, gentlemen.
军械官,你没事吧?
You ok, master gunny?
没事,好得不得了
Perfect. Abso-fucking-lutely perfect.
目标状态:目标已摧毁
Target status: Target destroyed.
他开枪了
He made that damn shot.
真不敢相信 他居然开枪
I can't believe it. He made that goddamn shot!
游戏结束
Game over.
你们的埋伏差点就被识破了
Your position was about to be compromised.
你的命令是取消任务
Your directive was to abort that mission.
我们是陆战队侦察狙击手,上尉
We're marine scout snipers, captain.
我们誓死达成任务
We don't abort missions unless we stop breathing.
你不该开枪 谁都不该开枪
You weren't supposed to make that shot. No one's supposed to.
反正我完成了我的任务
Well, I completed my mission.
想当年…
Back in my days...
好汉不提当年勇
Fuck your days!
全世界找不到
That was the luckiest fuckin' shot
那么狗屎运的一枪
in the history of lucky fuckin' shots!
上尉,抱歉毁了你的兵器
Sorry I broke your toy, captain.
一个狙击手如果要靠那种烂兵器 早就毙了
But if a sniper had to depend on that, he'd end up dead.
战场上可不像玩电动玩具 必须枪枪致命
It's not a video game out there.
必须枪枪致命
It's all about one shot and one kill.
你是害群之马,你知道吗?
You're a risk, you know that?
你把我们害惨了…
You're a goddamn liability
我自己不愿意再负担…
that I, for one, am not going to risk...
听不下去了是不是?
Getting bored, are we?
没占到你宝贵的喝酒时间吧?
I'm not cutting into your precious drinking time, am I?
恕我直言,长官 你说的没错,长官
Begging the captain's pardon, sir,
你说的没错,长官
but yes, sir, I am. And yes, sir, you are, sir.
我不喜欢你,中士军械官
I don't like you, master gunnery sergeant.
我不管你跟陆战队签下什么鸟契约
And I don't care about that fucking deal you made with the corps!
你要是下礼拜体检没过
You fail that medical next week,
回到真实世界我就让你好看
I'll Bury your ass back in the real world.
我说到做到
And that's a promise.
是的,谢谢长官
Yes, sir. Thank you, sir.
我找到你的狙击手了
I got him. Get your sniper.
恭喜你,尼尔 嘿,朋友
Congratulations, Neil.
你好朋友。
Hey, buddy.
恭喜
congratulations.
尼尔,干得好
Hey, nice going, Neil, buddy. Good job.
妈,来吧
Mom, mom, it's time.
不要,他说他会来的
No, he said he'd be here.
没关系
It's ok.
我昨天才跟他说的
I talked to him yesterday...
来吧,电视台的人 要拍我们切蛋糕
Come on, Neil, the t.V. People want a shot of us cutting the cake.
不能再等了
We can't wait any longer.
好吧
Ok.
妈,对不起
Sorry, mom.
反而像竞选宣传照
This looks more like a campaign photo opportunity
这不像婚礼
than a wedding.
今天我们就不发表演讲了…
We've decided to forgo the speeches today
因为有人实在无法到场
because of an unavoidable absence.
如果你是指贝克特
If that's Beckett you're talking about,
他大概在去酒吧途中迷路了
he probably got lost on the way to the bar.
他说得不错
Well, he's right.
不先喝两杯实在不行
No way I could do this without a couple of tall ones.
希妮
Sydney.
你知道我会赶来的
You knew I'd make it.
该我上了?
Do me the honors?
好
Ok.
老实说,我还真怕这种应酬
Actually, these kind of affairs scare the hell out of me.
尼尔
Neil.
多年前,你老爸 要我答应他一件事
Many years ago, your old man made me promise him something.
那就是,如果他无法参加你的婚礼…
That, were he not able to attend your wedding day,
就要我向你读这封信
I would read this letter to you.
如果让那步兵贝克特读这封信
""If that grunt Beckett is reading this,""
表示我已经一命呜呼了
""then I didn't make it.""
我希望这封信的这个部分
""I'm hoping this part of the letter""
在你的婚礼中宣读
""is being read at your wedding.""
我只想让你知道 我爱你…
""I just wanted to let you know that I love you,""
我要祝你和新娘永浴爱河
""and that I wish you and your bride nothing but happiness.""
永远爱她、疼惜她
""Love her and Cherish her always.""
祝你们长命百岁…
""And may you both live as long as you want,""
永远不逮吃穿
""and never want as long as you live.""
尼尔,这封信我已经保存很久了
Neil, I've been holding onto this for a long time.
现在交给你
Now I think it's yours.
恭喜
Congratulations.
谢谢你,汤姆
Thanks, Tom.
乔瑟琳与尼尔芬尼根
Jocelyn and Neil Finnegan.
每次看到尼尔 就觉得可惜保罗无法像他一样
Every time I look at Neil, I see the man Paul never got to be.
我相信他爸爸会以他为傲
Well, I'm sure his father would be very proud of him.
嗯嗯
Mmm-hmm.
你知道吗?这都是演戏
You know, this is a circus.
她已着眼白宫
She's got her eyes set on the white house,
非得让他入主白宫不可
and won't stop till she gets him there.
他是英烈战士的儿子…
He's the son of a war hero,
在安纳波里斯的哈佛政府学院 第一名毕业
graduates first in his class at Annapolis,
哈佛政府学院
Harvard school of government.
嗯嗯
Mmm-hmm.
在政坛平步青云
Climbing his way up the political ladder
为人诚恳,工作勤奋
with honest living and hard work.
我支持他 我也是
Hell, he's got my vote. Mine, too.
你的手会抖,什么时候开始的?
You're hand's shaking. When did that start?
几个月了,没事的
Ah, it's a few months ago. It's nothing.
也许没事,也许有事
Might be, might not.
你应该到我的诊所来让我看看
You should stop by the office and let me look at it, hmm?
汤姆,好啦
Tom, come on.
好啦
Ok.
我们是陆战队侦察狙击手
We're marine scout snipers.
长官,我们誓死达成任务
The only time we abort a mission
致死方休
is when we stop breathing, sir.
这是个很大的错误
It's a very big mistake.
除了明显原因之外,在从欧洲回来之后 他的举止记录…
Besides the obvious, his conduct record since returning from Europe
一直不佳
has been questionable.
心理测试结果有些不良 而且他根本…
Psychs are a bit disturbing. And he's just
年纪太大
old.
他年纪和我一样大
He's the same age I am.
我们可能只有一次机会
We may get one shot and one shot only.
我要贝克特出任务
I want Beckett taking it.
你的手指切除后 神经受到损害
You suffered nerve damage when you lost the finger.
此后就每下愈况
The condition's been steadily deteriorating ever since.
指腱…
The digitorum tendon,
功能正常时,可延伸舒张手指
when functioning normally, flexes and extends the finger.
但在受伤的手上…
But here on the damaged hand,
可能随时做出不随意的反射动作
you could have an involuntary reflex at any time.
在非常紧张的状况下 更容易发生
And it's more likely to occur in a high-stress situation.
汤姆,我觉得
What I see here, Thomas,
这也像是早期瘫痪症状
also looks like the early stages of palsy.
你不能一辈子当陆战队
You can't be a marine forever, you know.
我知道
Yeah, I know.
我能当到65岁就很满足了
I was just hoping to make it to 65.
你知道吗?你应该考虑开创新生活
You know, you should think about getting on with your life.
什么生活?
And do what?
嗯,应该找个伴侣,安定下来
Well, you should meet someone special, you know, settle down.
哦
Oh.
是呀
Yeah.
你自己怎么不找呢?
Why didn't you?
我找到了
Well, I did.
不过我跟保罗一起那几年 已经够了
But I guess, uh, the few years I had with Paul were enough.
而且,你对我也没兴趣
And besides, you never asked me.
嘿
Hey.
嗯
Mmm-hmm.
我们三个一起时,乐事还真不少
We had some good times, the 3 of us.
记得当年在乐荣营的事吗?
Down at camp lejeune, remember?
是的。
Yeah.
啊，西德……
Ah, Syd...
别…
Don't.
他没活着回来
He didn't come back.
许多年轻人都没能活着回来
A lot of young men didn't come back.
不要待在那间破烂的汽车旅馆 何不搬来跟我们住?
Why don't you get out of that horrible motel and come and stay with me?
哦
Oh.
好吧
Well.
事实上 我这辈子一直以行军袋为家
Tell you the truth, I've been living out of a sea bag all my life.
再几个礼拜 训练课程就结束了
I've only got a few more weeks of the training sessions,
然后军方就会把我载到 一个勤务站
then the corps will just ship me out to some other duty station somewhere.
那你要抽空约我吃饭
Then you should call me sometime and ask me to dinner,
我已经30年没约会了
I haven't had a date in 30 years.
这事请千万不要告诉别人
Syd, I'd really appreciate it if you didn't tell anyone about this.
没问题
Ok.
谢谢
Thanks.
再见
See you.
陆战队的
Jarheads.
干掉他
Kill him! Kill him!
Kill him!
发狂
Madness.
贝克特,我们走别留在这里
Beckett, let's go, let's go!
走吧 走吧 走吧
Let's get out of here! Let's go, let's go!
该死,他们越来越近了
Goddamn, they're getting close!
好极了
I love it!
掩护我,贝克特
Just cover my ass, Beckett.
妈的
Shit!
芬尼根 芬尼根
Finnegan! Finnegan!
让他躺下 让他躺下
Lay him down. Lay him down.
汤姆,你没事的
You'll be ok, Tommy.
你不会有事的
You're going to be ok.
欢迎来到隧道,汤姆
Welcome to the tunnels, Tommy.
什么都看不到
Can't see a goddamn thing.
慢慢你就习惯了
You'll get used to it.
这里是最危险的地方 来,拿着这个
It's where the real shit happens, man. Here, take this.
这是什么?
What is it?
幸运符 我前几天从一个越军身上拿下的
Good luck. Took it off a gook a couple of days ago.
北越军的混帐
N.v.a. Motherfuckers!
军械官,你没有回答
You didn't answer, master guns.
你的门没锁
Your door was unlocked.
如果我要小歧把我叫醒
If I wanted clowns to wake me up,
我早就加入马戏团了
I would've joined the circus.
军械官,恕我直言
With all due respect, master guns,
你应该去演喜剧
you should've been a comedian.
你到底想干嘛?
What the hell do you want?
军械官 我们奉命带您去会见高级长官
We have orders to take you in to go see the brass, master gunnery sergeant.
得了吧 我才不想会见高级长官
Yeah, well, I don't want to see the brass.
带他去冲澡
Let's get him in the shower.
长官,您可在陆战队顶尖的狙击手中
Sir, you could have your pick
挑选十二位
of a dozen of the corps' best snipers.
艾佛斯下士特别杰出
Corporal evers is a particularly good shot.
我对他没兴趣
I'm not interested in him.
我想要汤玛斯贝克特
I'm interested in Thomas Beckett.
这是国家安全委员会副主席 威廉埃瓦瑞
This is n.S.A. Deputy director William Avery.
我们认识,上尉 我们一起服役过
We know each other, captain. We served together.
上一辈子,长官
A lifetime ago, sir.
我有幸合作过的狙击手中 最厉害的一位
Best goddamn sniper I had the privilege of working with.
谢谢长官,找我有事吗?
Well, thank you, sir. What can I do for you?
汤姆,你明天上飞机
Tom, I want you on a plane tomorrow.
去哪儿,长官?
To where, sir?
越南
Vietnam.
长官
Captain.
我要你去除掉一个人
I want you to take out a target there.
彭霸来的一个山寨主 他和他的叛军…
A mountain warlord from phum bat. He and his rogue army
走私鸦片、武器
are running opium, stolen goods, weapons,
任何弄得到的东西都肯做
almost anything they can get their hands on.
听起来好像让越南人很头痛,长官
Sounds like a pain in the ass for the Vietnamese, sir.
我们为何要插手?
Why are we getting involved?
他已准备从事更危险的勾当
He's graduated to bigger and better things.
根据情报判断,我们相信…
We have intelligence that leads us to believe
他已和贾玛伊斯兰米雅在谈生意
he's been talking business with the jamaah islamiyah.
哪一种生意?
Oh, what kind of business?
恐怖事件
Terrorism.
他已开始玩大的
He's ventured into the big leagues.
长官,恕我直言 这里没什么资料
Well, with all due respect, sir, there's not very much here.
我们知道他长什么样子吗?
Do we even know what he looks like?
拉瑞比上尉 你出去一下好吗?
Captain laraby, would you mind excusing us?
没问题,长官
Of course not, sir.
阿迪斯
Addis.
芬尼根
Finnegan.
谢谢你,汤姆
Thanks, Tom.
他的尸体已运回家
His body was shipped home.
那只是一具尸体
What was left of the body.
尸体
A body.
说来话长,汤姆
It's a long story, Tom.
我大概解释一下
Let me try to explain some of it.
西贡沦陷的几天前
During the last days before the fall of Saigon,
保罗芬尼根接受征召
Paul Finnegan was recruited.
谁的征召?
Recruited by who?
中央情报局
The c.I.A.
他参与的第一个行动是协助赤棉军
His first op was to help the khmer Rouge
将海洛英运离高地
run heroin out of the highlands.
他这份利润可用来资助秘密行动
His cut financed the covert operations.
几年下来,我们的利益有所改变
As the years passed, our interests changed.
我们要芬尼根参与新的行动
Finnegan was offered a new op,
但丛林已改变了他
but the jungle had changed him.
当初的爱国情操已变质…
That patriotic fervor had changed into something else,
他成为一个危险人物
something that makes him dangerous.
他是一个能构成威胁的人
He's a threat.
对于你、我、他的家人、他的国家
To you, me, his family, and his country.
欢迎来到隧道,汤姆
Welcome to the tunnels, Tommy.
他到底在这里干嘛?
What the hell's he doing here?
有没有其他方法可处理这件事?
Is there any other way to handle this?
用谈的或是做一些安排?
A deal or an arrangement?
没有其他方法
There's no other way.
我们知道胡志明市警察…
We've learned the ho chi minh police
已展开部署来捕捉他
have set up a sting to capture him.
不能让他们这样做
That cannot happen.
若他被找到 你可想像
If he is identified, you can imagine
我们会有多大麻烦
the problems that we might face.
要费多大唇舌解释 更别提对于他家人的影响…
The explanations. Not to mention the effect on his family,
他的儿子…
his son...
你要我去杀死我的救命恩人
You're asking me to kill the man who saved my life.
我知道你一定觉得这个处境非常困难 汤姆…
I know how incredibly bizarre this must seem to you, Tom,
但相信我 他已经不是当年你所认识的他了
but believe me, this is not the man that you once knew.
几年下来 他已成为一个冷血杀手
Over the years, he has become a cold-blooded killer.
我很遗憾地说
And I'm ashamed to say,
我们对此有部分责任…
we bear some responsibility for that
也有义务矫正这个错误
and, uh, an obligation to rectify the mistake.
作为狙击手,你有权拒绝这次任务
As a sniper, you have the option to refuse the mission.
但你必须尽快决定
But I need an answer, Tom.
在明早八点前
By 0800.
如果你拒绝的话我能了解
I'll understand if you can't do this.
我会再找其他人
I'll find somebody else.
不
No.
我独自一人来做
I'll do it. Alone.
我不要有人监督
I want no observer with me.
我不要任何人插手
I don't want anybody else's hand in it.
你怎能确定到时候 他真下得了手?
How can you be so sure he'll do it when the time comes?
他总会千方百计 把事办成的
One way or another,
这是他生存的意义
he will get the job done.
只有在出生入死或夺人性命时
It's all he's got left.
他的命才稍有价值
His life isn't worth a damn
除非他冒险，或者拿别人的
unless he's risking it, or taking someone else's.
第一次来胡志明市吗?
First time in ho chi minh?
上次我来时,这里还叫西贡
Last time I was here, it was called Saigon.
汤玛斯贝克特
Uh, Beckett, Thomas.
贝克特先生,欢迎来到胡志明市
Welcome to ho chi minh, Mr. Beckett.
第一次来越南吗?
First time in Vietnam?
不是
No.
要不要点好康的,先生?
Do you want anything, sir?
你知道我的意思吧
If you know what I mean, you know?
我知道你的意思 真的不用了
Yeah, I know what you mean, and thanks but no thanks.
你确定吗?凯蔓什么都愿意做的
Sure? Because ky mam can get you anything.
包君满意
Anything that you want.
要不要马杀鸡?
Any good massage?
快乐一下
Uh, happy ending.
谢谢先生
Thank you, sir.
先生,您的袋子到了
Your bag has arrived, sir.
你一定送错房间
You must have the wrong room.
我已经拿到袋子了
I already have my bags.
不是这个 汤玛斯贝克特军械官
Not this one, master gunnery sergeant Thomas Beckett.
我叫关 胡志明市警局探员
My name is quan. Detective, Ho Chi Minh City police.
也是您行动的连络人
Also your operations contact.
那徽章唬不了我
Like I give a shit about some badge.
这次行动代号是什么?
What's the operation code name?
眼镜蛇
Cobra.
进来吧
Come on in.
那件衬衫还真有意思
Interesting choice of shirt.
看起来好像加拿大游客
You look like a Canadian tourist.
您会在此找到所需要的东西
You'll find what you need here.
他们说您能百发百中
They say you can make million-to-one shot.
您是个可靠的人吧?
You are the go-to guy. Yes?
他们真多嘴
They say a lot of things.
您远道而来,先休息 然后我们吃晚饭再聊
You rest after your trip, then we have some dinner. We talk.
我带您去探地点
I show you the spot.
11:30 准备好
Be ready at 11:30.
勾起您的回忆吗,贝克特先生?
This bring back memories, Mr. Beckett?
他们透露了一些您的事
They told me a little about you.
两次任务从头到尾参与
2 full tours.
您在这里时,正好是情况最糟时
You were here for the worst of it.
当时一切都很糟
None of it was good.
您当时一定很年轻
You must have been very young.
废话少说
Ok.
除了你以外,还有谁知道我来了?
Who else knows I'm here besides you?
如果您是指胡志明的警察 没有人知道
If you're talking about the ho chi minh police, no one.
如果他们知道,我早就没命了
If they knew, I'd be a dead man.
好吧,我们怎样行动?
All right, then how do we work this?
我如何寻找我的目标?
How do I find my target?
两周前,我在胡志明市 逮到了他最大的毒贩…
2 weeks ago, I arrested his biggest dealer in Ho Chi Minh City,
然后劝服他为我们指认眼镜蛇
and convinced him to, uh, how do you say, to finger the cobra for us.
为什么叫他眼镜蛇?
Why do you call him that?
他们把他捧得像王一样 眼镜蛇王
They treat him like he's a king. King cobra.
他们其实只是小孩子 有些才不过十几岁
They're just kids, really. Some barely in their teens.
把头切下来,蛇也活不成 相信我
You cut off the head, the snake will die, believe me.
那毒贩告诉我们
The dealer told us about a meeting
眼镜蛇要和一个新客户碰面
between cobra and a new client.
我们会去那里逮捕他
We will be there to arrest him.
你抢先一步,先把他干掉
You take him out before that happens.
在西贡这里吗?
Here in Saigon?
西贡?
Saigon?
还改不了口是不是?
Old habits die hard, huh?
在眼镜蛇开的一家店里 共军俱乐部
At one of the establishments the cobra owns. Club cong.
看看这个
Check this out.
这是最新型的
This is very new.
我会叫那毒贩放在眼镜蛇身上
I'm going to make the dealer put it on the cobra.
你的TRS电脑会收到信号
It'll send a signal to your t.R.S. Computer.
那样就容易在人群中找到他
That way it'll be easy to find him in the crowd.
顺便问一下 你的武器如何?
By the way, how are your weapons?
AW麦格农还不错 你去哪弄来的?
The a.W. Magnum's just fine. Where did you get that?
他妈的日本鬼子的,很酷吧?
Fucking Japanese. Pretty cool, huh?
我能多靠近我的目标?
How close do I get to my target?
大概300公尺吧,包括室内室外
300 meters, maybe. Outside, inside.
吃完我带你去看
Come on, eat up. I think it's best I show you.
你做警察多久了?
How long have you been a policeman?
6年
6 years.
国家安全委员会何时征召你的?
When did the n.S.A. Recruit you?
两年前,你知道怎样吗?
Couple of years ago. You see how it is?
现在比从前好不到哪去
No better than before.
要有些改变才行
Things need to change.
也许你们就不会像上次一样搞砸
Maybe you guys don't fuck up like last time.
你老爸也打过仗吗?
Was your old man in the war?
对
Yes.
北越军？
N.v.a.?
我爸是美国大兵
My father was an American g.I.,
第九营,25步兵连
9th battalion, 25th infantry.
这里没有人知道这件事
Nobody here knows this.
在这里死的吗?
He die here?
回到他家人那里了 在俄亥俄州
Went home to his real family somewhere in Ohio.
看到那个屋顶没有?
There. You see that roof?
那就是共军俱乐部
That's club cong.
今晚约10:00你的目标将会到那里
Your target will be there tonight around 10:00.
他通常坐在上层的位子
He usually sits at a table on the upper deck.
会很热闹吗?
Will it be crowded?
通常会
It usually is.
他从哪个方向来呢?
What about the street? He's got to come and go.
入口在另一边
The entrance is on the other side.
取不到狙击角度
There's no sniper angle.
开枪之后 你把武器丢在这里
After you take the shot, you abandon your weapon here,
然后买张往谭松的火车票
and buy a ticket on tan son train.
我带你去机场
It'll take you to the airport.
善后呢?
What about the cleanup?
我已安排好新的身份证
A new identification has been arranged.
尸体不会有人去认领
The body will not be claimed.
警察会很高兴眼镜蛇已被除掉
Police will be satisfied the cobra is dead
而且没人会知道他到底是谁
and no one will know who he really was.
贝克特先生
Mr. Beckett.
事成之后我不会和你见面
I will not see you after this.
这是我手机号码
That's my cell phone number.
除非你需要什么或事情不妙 否则不要打
Call only if you need something or if something is wrong.
记住
And remember,
也许你只有机会开一枪
one shot is probably all you get.
我只需要一枪
One shot is all I need.
一切都已就绪,行动已展开
Everything is in place. The op is on-line.
How's Beckett doing?
贝克特如何?
国家安全委员会总部 马里兰州密德堡
我们连络人说他很好
Our contact says he's fine.
没有犹豫吗?
No hesitations?
似乎没有
Doesn't seem so.
目标呢?
Target?
此刻正在行动中 他的买主来了
On the move as we speak. His buyer has arrived.
目前为止一切顺利
So far, so good.
若一切顺利
If everything goes well, it'll be over in
十小时之内就能完成
less than 10 hours.
这样最好
From your lips to god's ear.
因为如果不这样
'Cause if it doesn't,
我们大家都会倒大楣
we're all in deep shit.
你好
Hello.
是我
It's me.
汤玛斯?
Thomas?
对
Yeah.
现在是凌晨4:00 有什么问题吗?
It's 4:00 in the morning. Is something wrong?
希妮,对不起,我…
Oh, Sydney, i'm... I'm sorry, I...
你的声音听起来好远 你在哪里?
You sound so distant. Where are you?
嗯…
Oh...
大概30年的距离
About 30 years away.
汤玛斯?
Thomas?
对不起,希妮,真抱歉吵醒了你
I'm sorry, Syd. I'm... I'm sorry for waking you. I...
你没事吧?
Are you ok?
我没事,只是…
I'm ok. I just...
我一直在想…
I've been thinking about
你和尼尔如何…
how you and Neil are...
你们是…
You're
我最亲近的人了
the closest thing I've ever had to a family.
我知道…
And I... I know
有时候我…
sometimes I...
有时候我忘记 这对我是多么珍贵
Sometimes I forget how much that's meant to me.
我只是想要…
And I just wanted to
确定你们真的知道
make sure you knew.
我们知道,汤玛斯
We know, Thomas.
我们知道
We know.
你真的没事吗?
Are you sure you're ok?
没事
Yeah. I'm ok.
那我不多说了
Look, I gotta go.
嗯
Um,
我会……我会，呃，
I'll tell you what. I'll... I'll, uh,
我过几天打电话给你
I'll give you a call in a few days,
等我回来以后
you know, after I get back.
你保证?
You promise?
对,我保证
I promise. Yeah.
你知道我爱你
You know I love you.
我爱你
I love you.
我也是
Me, too.
你他妈的在看什么
What the fuck are you lookin' at?
你要我去杀死我的救命恩人
You're asking me to kill the man who saved my life.
他到底在这里干嘛?
What the hell's he doing here?
许多年轻人都没能活着回来
A lot of young men didn't come back.
妈的 真该死
Goddamn piece of shit.
去做吧
Do it.
妈的
Shit.
就现在
Now!
抱歉
Forgive me.
该死
Damn.
搞定 混蛋
Got you, fucker.
你他妈的不怎么准
You're not that good a fucking shot,
但也许可以靠运气
but you might get lucky.
刚刚到底怎么回事?
What the hell happened?
贝克特没打中目标
Beckett missed the target.
可是他妈的打到我们后备人员吗?
But he took out our goddamn backup?
我们完蛋了,真的完蛋了
We're fucked, truly fucked.
他现在在哪里?
Where is he now?
被越南警察带走了
The Vietnamese police have him.
我们的人应该很容易接近他吧?
It should be easy for our men to get to him, right?
我们连络人没有受过那种训练
Our contact is not trained for that.
那就找一个受过那种训练的人
Then get someone who is.
应该是我跟他谈才对
Talk to me.
我说过,我叫贝克特
I told you, my name is Beckett.
汤玛斯杰贝克特
Thomas j. Beckett.
你在这里做什么? 汤玛斯杰贝克特
And what are you doing here, Thomas j. Beckett?
努力学习亚洲文化
Soakin' up Asian culture.
你在屋顶上杀的那个人
The man you killed on the roof,
是柬埔寨国民
he was Cambodian national.
也许你们两个和今晚
Maybe you two got something to do
在共军俱乐部发生的事有关
with what happened at club cong tonight.
共军俱乐部?
Club cong?
我要找美国领事
Look, I want to speak to the American consul.
没问题
Sure. You bet.
国家警察已接管了这个案子
The national police have taken over the case.
当你忘记告诉我…
You should have thought of that
事迹败露该如何处理时
when you changed the plan and forgot
就该想到会有这种后果
to tell me about the secondary hit.
我来想办法
I'll see what I can do.
靠,这世界上怪事还真多 是不是,老汤?
Weird fucking world, ain't it, Tommy?
芬尼根?
Finnegan?
靠
Fucking weird.
这么多年以后
After all these years,
他们居然找 我亲密的老战友来干掉我
they send my old hump buddy Beckett to do the job.
那是埃瓦瑞的主意吧?
That was Avery's idea, wasn't it?
怎会失手?
What happened?
你一向能百发百中的
You could always make the million-to-one shot.
太久没练,还是改变心意?
Losing your touch, or change of heart?
该死的埃瓦瑞骗你
Fucking Avery lied to you, Tommy.
他也骗了我
That's something the two of us have in common.
他哪里说谎?
Which lie?
有关你贩毒吗?
The one about you dealing drugs?
还是走私武器?
Or running weapons?
还是贾玛伊斯兰米雅?
Or the jamaah islamiyah?
这他们也知道?
They know about that, huh?
为什么,老芬?
Why, Finn?
被逼上绝路,还有什么选择?
What other choice does a dead man have?
我把生命奉献给上帝和国家
I gave my life to serve god and country.
你在跟死亡打交道
You're a dealer in death.
你奉献给谁的上帝、谁的国家?
Whose god and country do you serve?
最后一件事是
The last thing I need
来刺杀我还要跟我讲生命的大道理 省省吧你
is a sermon about death from an assassin.
我奉他们之命行事 却被他们出卖
I did the job they asked and they sold me out.
那么结束之后你为什么不回家?
Then why didn't you come home when it ended?
这里是我的家 这里一直是我的家
This is my home. It was always my home.
我们在西宁登陆的那一刹那 我就知道了
I knew it the second we hit that l.Z. In tay ninh.
过了第一个晚上之后 我就知道我不想回去了,老汤
After that first night, I knew I wasn't going back, Tommy.
我在这里如鱼得水
I was alive here!
即使出生入死,我还是快活得很
Even in all the death, I was alive!
来此之前,无论什么事、什么人
Nothing ever made me feel like that back there.
都不曾让我有这种感觉
Nothing and no one.
有的人天生就爱打仗
Some people are born for war.
这不是打仗,老芬
This isn't war, Finn.
这是疯狂之举
This is madness.
希妮跟尼尔呢?
What about Syd and Neil?
你知道,你儿子刚结婚
You know, your son just got married.
我依照诺言宣读了你的贺词
I delivered your note as promised.
他们不存在
They don't exist.
他们三十多年前消失了
They haven't existed for over 30 years.
最好别提起
It was better that way.
这样对大家都好
For everyone.
我开枪之后,有人想要杀我
Someone tried to kill me after I took the shot.
你现在无法脱身了
You're in it now.
你应该在还能逃时逃走的
You should have quit when you were ahead.
无法脱身?
In what?
我可以毁掉他们,老汤
I can Bury them, Tommy,
他们就怕这点
that's what they're afraid of.
你不是第一个来刺杀我的
You're not the first one to come gunning.
他们已经试了好几年
They've been trying for years.
所以我才留在壕沟里
That's why I stay in the ditch.
很抱歉,这是你自找的
Sorry you got yourself into this.
但话说回来,你一直是理想主义者
But then, you always were an idealist.
他们就是看中你这点
That's what they counted on, Tommy.
我觉得难过的是尼尔
Neil's the one I feel sorry for.
他觉得自己是战争英雄的儿子
He thinks he's the son of a war hero.
我每天看着这个世界沉沦入地狱
Every day, I watch this world descend into hell.
我只想找个舒服的位子
I'm just trying to find myself
好好观赏
a nice comfortable seat with a good view.
胡志明市警察局被人炸了
Somebody blew up the goddamn police station
什么?
at ho chi minh. What?
你好
Hello.
小子,你听好
Now, listen to me, you little fuck,
乖乖闭嘴
and don't you say a word.
过2小时跟我在 人民统一大楼碰面
Meet me at the people's unification building in 2 hours.
你一个人来…
You come alone
不然我会告诉胡志明的警察 你的幕后指使人是谁
or I'll tell the ho chi minh police who you really work for.
我不知道他们想要干嘛 他们从来没有…
I didn't know what they were gonna do. They never...
你好吗
Hello?
两方都在玩游戏
It was a game both sides played.
我不知道
Look, I didn't know.
他们从没跟我说 对你攻击是行动的一部份
They never told me the hit on you was part of the operation.
我发誓
I swear.
芬尼根怎么了?
What happened to Finnegan?
他们还不知道
They don't know yet.
他们还在指认尸体
They're still identifying bodies.
多年来我一直努力 想把这一切忘记
I've spent years trying to forget this shit.
你真的以为有这么容易吗?
You really think it was going to be that easy?
你要从这里救我出去
You're going to get me out of here.
然后去哪里?
And go where?
再拿给我一把来福枪 和一个随身武器
You're gonna get me another rifle and a sidearm.
然后去哪里?
And go where?
他如果还活着,一定在壕沟里
If he's alive, he's in the ditch.
参议员,请等一下
Hang on a sec, senator.
我们在金边有些人手
We had some people in Phnom Penh.
他们应该在一个小时内 就能赶到胡志明
They should be in ho chi minh in less than an hour.
坏消息是,我们的人不假外出
The bad news is that our boy's gone awol.
不假外出是什么意思?
What do you mean, awol?
他还没有报到
He hasn't checked in.
芬尼根和贝克特呢?
What about Finnegan and Beckett?
他们还在辨认尸体
They're still I.D.-ing bodies,
但两人都还不在死亡名单上
but neither of them are on the list so far.
妈的,怎么会搞成这样
I don't fucking believe this.
我再打电话给你
I'm going to have to call you back.
没事,已经控制住了
No, it's under control.
如果贝克特还活着 而且他找到我们的人…
If Beckett is still alive, and he's gotten to our boy...
我知道
I know.
你和芬尼根是朋友?
You and Finnegan were friends?
我是说,真正的好朋友?
I mean, real good friends?
对,他救过我一命
Yeah. He saved my ass once.
那你一定很难下手
This must be hard then.
是的
Yeah.
他是坏人
He's a bad guy.
我知道
I know.
你怎么知道他在西宁?
How do you know he's up in tay ninh?
不在市内,在地下
Not in. Under.
我认识芬尼根时,他是隧道鼠卧底人员
When I knew Finnegan, he was a tunnel rat.
大家都知道这些人 也知道他们做什么
Everybody knows about them, and what they did.
这还用说,他们是奉命行事
Yeah, well, they did what they had to do.
有人说自己喜欢这种工作
Some say they like it.
你是不该喜欢的
You're not supposed to like it.
你他妈的懂不懂战争啊?
What the fuck do you know about war?
你怎么确定他在那里?
How can you be sure he's there?
因为我在牢里时,他说溜了嘴
Because when I was in the jail, he slipped.
他提到什么""在壕沟里""
He mentioned something about ""being in the ditch.""
隧道鼠把隧道叫做壕沟
And that's what the rats called the tunnels.
我们要不要跟人连络?
Should we contact someone?
你还有可任的人吗?
Someone you can trust?
现在，我不相信任何人
Right now, I don't trust anybody.
靠,这是什么?
What the hell is that?
警察还是国家安全委员会?
Police or n.S.A.?
国家安全委员会
N.s.a.
他们在搜寻信号
They're in pursuit of the signal.
我们的人已前往西宁
Our boy's headed towards tay ninh.
贝克特和他在一起
Beckett's with him.
他在找芬尼根
He's goin' after Finnegan.
他在那里搞什么?
What the hell's he doing here?
和史提维约克打招呼
Say hello to Stevie York.
我们上六点新闻了
We're the 6:00 news, Tommy.
正午时有几个人经过这里
Some men came through here midday.
他们往丛林去了,有一个是白人
They headed into the jungle. One was white.
他回家了
He's headed home.
你以为自己一个人去
You really expect to go in there
能活着回来吗?
by yourself and come out alive?
不
No.
你要跟我一起去
You're goin' with me.
这对我有什么好处?
Why would I want to do that?
你想知道他们为何要干掉我
Well, you wanted to know why they tried to kill me.
答案就在芬尼根身上
The answer's in there with Finnegan.
你知道,有些事情他没有告诉我
You see, there's something he didn't tell me.
他们派我来的真正原因
The real reason they sent me.
依照计划,最后应该剩下他…
And it was supposed to end with him
和我
and me.
你这他妈是哪弄来的?
Where the hell did you dig this up?
这是我爸的
It's my father's.
他只留下这件东西
It's all he left behind.
我用它来学射击
I learned to shoot with it.
这枪好吗?
Is it ok?
不是我说 这是性能最好的狙击来福枪
Best damn sniper rifle ever made, if you ask me.
你没告诉我 你老爹是狙击手
You didn't tell me your old man was a sniper.
你没问我
You didn't ask.
我们的柬埔寨部队
Our Cambodian units found the cell phone
在去西宁的路边捡到手机
on the side of the road to tay ninh.
他们一定已发现这手机可被人跟踪
They must have figured out it was traceable.
不是他们,是贝克特
Not they. Beckett.
现在怎么办?
What do we do now?
叫他们继续找
Tell them to keep looking.
同时祈祷在贝克特找到芬尼根之前 先让他们找到贝克特
And pray to god that they find Beckett before he finds Finnegan.
越来越…
Hey, Beckett, it's getting...
小声点
Hold it down.
我们一定找不到这个地方
We're never going to find this place.
贝克特
Beckett.
还好吧?
You ok?
他们还有更多人
There's more of them.
他没弹药了,干掉他
He's dry. Get him! Get him!
他是最后一个
He's the last one.
他也许会往隧道去
He'll probably be heading for the tunnels.
那里
There.
他只是一个孩子
Ah, he's just a kid.
他要去警告他们
He was going to warn them.
对,我知道
Right. I know.
芬尼根知道我们已经来了
Finnegan knows we're here already.
这对他只是一场游戏
It's just a game to him.
第一圈我们赢了
We won the first round.
通过出发点,领200元
Pass go, collect $200.
现在轮到我们花钱了
Now it's our chance to spend it.
什么?
What?
这是一种游戏
It's a game.
你知道,像麻将一样?
You know, like mahjong?
紧跟着我,听我指示
Stay close to me and do as I say.
你怎么知道走哪条路?
How do you know which way to go?
我不知道
I don't.
惨
Great.
干脆喊话 让他们知道我们在这里
Why not just yell out and tell them we're here?
我们怎么看得见东西?
How're we going to see?
不要开灯
No lights.
走哪条?
Which way?
什么?
What?
我听到了
I hear it.
好像音乐
Sounds like music.
好像是NWA
Sounds like n.W.A.
什么?
What?
NWA,傲慢黑鬼乐团
N.w.a. Niggas with attitude.
就是方块冰、德瑞博士那些饶舌乐手
You know, ice cube, Dr. Dre? The rappers.
听起来像是《干掉警察》
Sounds like fuck tha police.
哪种白痴会写这种歌?
What kind of idiots would write a song like that?
你应该多听一点巴布希格
You ought to try listenin' to a little Bob seger.
什么?
What?
来吧,警察,拼个你死我活
Couldn't leave it alone, huh, Tommy?
让他走
Let him go.
他没有参与这档子事
He's not part of this.
太迟了
He is now.
你带他来,必有原因
You brought him along for a reason.
我想是中情局
I'm thinking agency.
也许是国家安全委员会
And maybe n.S.A.
我不想浪费你的时间来证明我自己 老汤
I'm not gonna waste your time trying to justify myself, Tommy.
我们都是杀手
We're both killers.
不一样的杀手
Different kinds.
我杀人,是因为他该杀
When I kill a man, it's because he needs killin'.
我看他这一辈子
I look at his life
没做什么好事,我才毙了他
and if it adds up to nothin', I take him out.
但是你,老芬
But you, Finn,
你把杀人变成乐趣
you got to likin' it.
我从来没有
I never did.
那这是怎么一回事,老芬?
So what's this all about, Finn?
最后怎会走到这步田地?
How does it all end here?
是史提维约克
It's about Stevie York.
你记得史提维吧?
You remember Stevie, don't you?
和史提维约克打招呼
Say hello to Stevie York.
他在这里搞什么?
What the hell's he doin' here?
美联社的摄影师?
The a.P. Photographer?
这是史提维、我和埃瓦瑞之间的事
It's about Stevie and me and Avery.
还有盖勒
And gaylor.
约翰盖勒,那个参议员?
John gaylor, the senator?
有些人说他马上会当上总统
Soon to be president, some say.
史提维怎样?
What about Stevie York?
他全都拍了下来
He filmed it all.
我们都吸了不少毒
We were higher than kites.
吸毒、狩猎 三天没合眼
Smokin' and huntin' for 3 days without sleep.
他们有9个人
There was 9 of them.
6男3女
6 men and 3 women.
拍完以后,我们开始有些紧张兮兮
When it was done, we started getting paranoid.
我们叫约克毁掉底片
We'd make York destroy the film.
但日子久了…
But as the days passed,
盖勒和埃瓦瑞一直对我施压
gaylor and Avery kept getting more and more psycho on me.
所以我们三个一言为定
So we made a pact, the 3 of us.
然后我们杀了史提维
And then we killed Stevie
做得像是北越军杀的
and made it look like the n.V.A. Did it.
现在呢?老汤
So what now, Tommy?
下一步怎么办?
What's our next move?
这样吧
Tell you what.
我放你一条生路 你回家
You could just walk out of here and go home.
如果我走,我要那个警察跟我一起走
If I leave, the cop goes with me.
走,快逃,贝克特
Go, get out, Beckett!
你知道我不能这样做
You know I can't let that happen, Tommy.
你必须杀掉我
You're going to have to kill me.
到这个地步,我只能杀掉他
The only way I see it from here is to kill him.
你的口头禅是什么?
What's your old sayin'?
一发子弹,一条命
""One shot, one kill.""
一发子弹,两条命,怎么样?
How about, one shot, 2 kills?
百发百中
A million-to-one.
他们不是曾经这样讲吗?
Isn't that what they used to say?
开枪,反正他们也不会放过我
Do it. They're gonna kill me one way or another.
他说得不错,老汤 发挥你的实力吧
He's right, Tommy. Take your best shot.
指腱可伸缩与舒张手指
The digitorum tendon flexes and extends the finger.
我们两人之间 有一人的大限快到了
Time's running out for one of us.
快,老汤,赶快
Come on, Tommy, make your move!
这是怎么回事?
Quan, what's happening here?
他们说你是猫鼬
They say you're the mongoose.
再说一遍
Come again?
猫鼬
The mongoose.
在古老的越南民间故事中
It's a... it's an old Vietnamese folk tale.
上帝创造眼镜蛇 立他为王
When god created the cobra, he made him king.
时间久了,眼镜蛇权力越来越大 以为自己是上帝
As time passed, the cobra became so powerful he thought he was god.
所以上帝又创造了猫鼬 把他的权力夺走
So god created the mongoose to take his power away.
嗯-嗯
Mmm-hmm.
他们想干嘛?
What do they want?
无论你想干嘛 现在权力在于你
Whatever you want. You have the power now.
你在开玩笑吧
You're kiddin' me.
是真的,我告诉你
It's true, I told you.
他们只是孩子,孩子什么都肯做
They're just kids. Kids do anything.
你听我说
Listen to me.
有一个麦肯纳上校
There's a colonel McKenna.
陆军情报部的丹麦肯纳上校
Colonel Dan McKenna. Military intelligence.
他驻在华府五角大厦
He's stationed at the Pentagon in Washington D.C.
我要你和他连络,不要找其他人
I want you to contact him and only him.
告诉他这里发生的事
Tell him what happened here.
告诉他过两天我需要 撤运伤军的直升机…
And tell him I'll need a dust-off in 2 days
在柬埔寨境内 磅河和梅河的交流处
where the kampong and mebon rivers meet in Cambodia.
为什么不和我一起回来?
Why not come back with me?
他们会在越南找我
They'll be looking for me in the nam.
我想对我比较安全
I think it's safer
越过边界去柬埔寨
if I d.D. Across the border into Cambodia.
你问问他们好吗?
Can you ask them that?
你信得过我吗?
You trust me to do this?
如果我两天后到那里
If in 2 days I get there,
却没有直升机带我走…
and there's not a chopper to evac me out,
那我大概看错了你
then I'll guess I was wrong about you.
Quan
Quan.
你也是
You, too.
嘿，贝克特。
Hey, Beckett.
你真是神枪手
You're one hell of a shot.
现在不行了
Was.
今日最新消息
In breaking news today, it was learned
据报德州参议员约翰盖勒…
that senator John gaylor from Texas
已辞去参议院席位
has resigned his seat in the senate.
在由发言人宣读的声明中
In his statement read by a spokesman,
参议员表示他决定…
the senator said he has decided
结束政治生涯
to end his political aspirations
在私人机构另求发展
and enter the private sector.
他的辞职完全
His resignation came as a complete surprise
在白宫意料之外
to the white house.
盖勒参议员被视为该党…
Senator gaylor was thought to be his party's leading candidate
下届总统大选的热门候选人
for the upcoming presidential race.
对于参议员辞职的消息…
The news of the senator's departure
总统一定感到非常头痛
must be very troubling for the president,
因为才在两天前…
considering it was just 2 days ago
他最信赖的顾问之一
that one of his most trusted advisors,
国家安全委员会副主席威廉埃瓦瑞…
William Avery, deputy director of the n.S.A.,
被发现自杀而身亡
was found dead, an apparent suicide.